BU Records: International Programs Office, Inclusive: 1976-2011, undated, Bulk: 1991-1998
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
BU Records: International Programs Office
Inclusive: 1976-2011, undated, Bulk: 1991-1998
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
BU/341
Baylor University
5 document boxes.
BU Records: International Programs Office contains materials largely related to Baylor's international partnerships and programs. Materials contain correspondence, pamphlets, research materials, photographs, and administrative materials.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Good.
Biography/Profile
Baylor University's International Programs Office was the department dedicated to administering the international activities of the university. Abroad, this meant establishing partnerships with foreign universities and educators in places as diverse as Europe, the Middle East, East Asia, and Southeast Asia. These organizations include Yonok College in Thailand, a partnership that began in 1981. Domestically, the office assisted foreign exchange students at Baylor. This included providing academic guidance and scheduling social events, such as talent shows and food festivals.
Scope and Content
BU Records: International Programs Office consists of materials from 1976-2011, with some undated items. These materials reflect the work of the office with international organizations and students at Baylor and abroad.
Series I. Administrative Materials consists of correspondence, financial records, meeting minutes, and event-related documents. Series II: Photographs consists of photo albums and photograph slides.
Arrangement
Prior to processing, this collection came organized in labeled folders with titles and dates. The slides came undated. For the current round of processing, the majority of the folder titles were retained during processing. The folders have been organized alphabetically by subject.
Currently, the collection includes two series: 1. Administrative Materials and II. Photographs.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. BU/341. Acquired 2001-12-01
Related Resources
Related references
Baylor University. "Baylor to Host Food Fest for International Community Oct. 12." News Release. 1991 October 4.
BU Records: International Programs Office, Accession #BU/341, Box #5, Folder #4-5, the Texas Collection, Baylor University.
Ford, Gerry. “Reynolds Visits Baylor Alumnus at Thai College.” The Lariat, 1988 March 1.
Index Terms
Subjects (Organizations)
Baylor University -- Records and correspondence.; Baylor University -- Students.; Maha¯witthaya¯lai Yo¯nok.
Places
Thailand
Subjects
China -- Education (Higher).; Correspondence.; Kurdistān (Iraq) -- Education (Higher).; Minutes (Records); Photographs.; Records (Documents); Students, Foreign.; Thailand -- Education (Higher).
- Administrative Materials, 1976-2011, undated.; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Excellent.
  Biography/Profile
  This series contains correspondence, meeting minutes, financial records, event plans, and contracts between organizations. This series is in excellent condition.
  - American Collegiate Consortium for East-West Cultural Academic Exchange (1 of 3), 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - American Collegiate Consortium for East-West Cultural Academic Exchange (2 of 3), 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - American Collegiate Consortium for East-West Cultural Academic Exchange (3 of 3), 1991-1993 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - American Philippine Educational Foundation, 1989-1995 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - American-Polish Foundation for Education, 1976-1995 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Association of Southeast Asian Institute of Higher Learning, 1992-2000 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - American Thai Foundation, 2004-2011 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Dr. Asmat Khalid — Baylor Visit and Meeting with President Sloan and Provost Jeffery, 2004 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - English as a Second Language (1 of 3), 1994-1998 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - English as a Second Language (2 of 3), 1994-1998 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - English as a Second Language (3 of 3), 1994-1998 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - International Conference on Energy and Environment, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Dr. Nirund Jivasantikarn, 2002-2008 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Dr. Nirund Jivasantikarn, 2002-2008 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Dr. Nirund Jivasantikarn, 2002-2008 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Philanthropy Gala, 2003 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - President Sloan — Trip to Thailand, 2003-2004 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Provost David L. Jeffrey — Meeting, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Recruitment Trip to Thailand and Turkey, 2005 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Thailand Delegation (1 of 2) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Thailand Delegation (2 of 2), 2007 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Universities of Salahaddin, Arbil, and Dohuk in Kurdistan (1 of 2), 1994-1996 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Universities of Salahaddin, Arbil, and Dohuk in Kurdistan (2 of 2), 1994-1996 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Vision 2012 — Imperative II — Report to President Sloan, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Visits from Yonok and Lampang Guests, 2003-2007 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Visits from Yonok and Lampang Guests, 2003-2007 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Yonok College (1 of 5), 1987-1998 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Yonok College (2 of 5), 1987-1998 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Yonok College (3 of 5), 1987-1998 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Yonok College (4 of 5), 1987-1998 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Yonok College (5 of 5), 1987-1998 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Yunnan Institute of the Nationalities (1 of 3), 1984-1994 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Yunnan Institute of the Nationalities (2 of 3), 1984-1994 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Yunnan Institute of the Nationalities (3 of 3), 1984-1994 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Photographs, 1982-1986, undated.; 2
  This series contains the pages of photo albums and photo slides of international student activities. The series in excellent condition.
  Index Terms
  Genres
  35 mm slide; Photograph album
  - Photo Album, 1982-1983 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Photo Album, 1986, undated. (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Photograph Slides, undated (Box 6 OVZ)